# Víctor Ponce López



#### Contact

vponcelop<at>gmail.com victorponce.site Bristol, United Kingdom

#### Languages

Catalan \*\*\*\*(native),
Spanish \*\*\*\*(native),
English \*\*\*\*

(advanced reading/writing, fluent oral),

Français \*\*\*\*\*
(intermediate reading/writing, basics oral).

#### Programming Languages, Libs, Tools, Web and Environments

♥ Python, MATLAB, C++/C#/C, R, PyCharm, Netbeans, Eclipse, VS/VC++, SVN/GIT, Redmine, ੴEX, XML, PostgreSQL, SQL, MySQL, Hive, Spark, Hadoop, CodaLab, Kaggle, Bash, PHP/HTML/CSS/JavaScript;

Deep Learning & Computer
Vision libraries and toolboxes:
▼ Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras,
GAN, CNN, LSTM, dlib,
CUDA+CuDNN, Kinect™SDK,
open{CV/NI/GL}, CNTK+;
evolutionary computation and
statistical pattern recognition:
▼ numpy, matplotlib, sklearn,
optimtool, gatool, pmtk3,
deap, pandas, statsmodel.

#### **OS Preferences**

GNU/Linux \*\*\*\*
Windows \*\*\*\*
MacOS \*\*\*\*
Android \*\*\*\*
iOS \*\*\*\*

## **short** bio

I am a Research Associate in the Dept. of Computer Science at the University of Bristol. I was a Research Scientist in Eurecat at the Big Data Analytics Unit. I hold a PhD at the the Dept. of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Barcelona (UB). I received my B.Sc. degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Faculty of Mathematics of UB, and my M.Sc. degree in Artificial Intelligence at the Polytechnic University of Catalonia (UPC). I was affiliated to the Computer Vision Center -Autonomous University of Barcelona (UAB)- and the Open University of Catalonia (UOC), in the groups HuPBA and SUNAI; and the group Qarma at the Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentalle (LIF), Aix-Marseille Université.

# **experience**

2017-Present University of Bristol

Bristol, United Kingdom

Postdoctoral Research Associate, Dept. of Computer Science.

- Time-Series Predictive Analysis of Seasonal Ground Surface Deformation.
- Computer Vision for Human Activity Recognition in Home Healthcare.
- Domain Adaptation, Self-Supervised Learning, GANs, Person Re-IDentification.

2010–2017 Eurecat Technology Center of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, Open University of Catalonia, Computer Vision Center, and Dept. of Justice, Government of Catalonia

Research Scientist, PostDoc, Collaboration in Research projects, international PhD stay, 40+ scientific publications and peer-reviews, teaching and material preparation, organization/attendance on international conferences, events, and seminars.

- 4 impact factor journals, 17 conference proceedings, and 1 book chapter.
- ChaLearn Looking At People collaboration with Microsoft, NVIDIA, Google, Amazon, Disney, Facebook, Orange, MWC-GSMA.
- · Research projects on human behavior analysis within real-world domains.

Past-2010 Barcelona's Council: Dept. of Education, Culture and Welfare

Barcelona, Spain

Software Engineer, IT Services.

## education

2012–2016 Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona

Dissertation: "Evolutionary Bags of Space-Time Features for Human Analysis." Cum

Laude (spanish) and International Mention.

2010–2012 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence

Polytechnic University of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, and Rovira i Virgili University.

Dissertation: "Multi-Modal Human Gesture Recognition combining Dynamic Program-

ming and Probabilistic Methods." With Honors.

2006–2010 B.Sc in Computer Science: Systems engineering

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona.

Dissertation: "Analysis of Oral and Gestural Expression using an Artificial Vision Sys-

tem." With Honors.

### extracurricular

2006-Present **Driving license** 

2004-Present Martial Arts licenses Hapkido 2<sup>nd</sup> Black Belt

1998-2004 Musical language and Piano licenses

### interests

I'm a research & technology passionate. My main interests are computer vision, machine learning, and evolutionary computation for real-world applications. I like to be up to date with latest research and cutting-edge technology to foresee next future trends and needs.